## **Curriculum Vitae - Xianglong Feng**

# CONTACT INFORMATION

CORE 533, Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering, Rutgers University 96 Frelinghuysen Rd, Piscataway, NJ 08854

Cell Phone: (402) 613-6237

E-mail: xf56@scarletmail.rutgers.edu

Website: xianglongfeng.net

#### **EDUCATION**

Rutgers University, the state university of New Jersey Ph.D. in Electrical and Computer Engineering

May 2021 (anticipated)

3 ...

Chinese Academy of Sciences

July 2015

M.S. in Computer Application Technology

China University of Petroleum B.S. in Communication Engineering

July 2012

## RESEARCH SUMMARY

My research has been focused on the multimedia system, including improving the user experience quality and resolving the security issues. I am interested in a wide range of technologies spanning the broad area of electronic and computer engineering, based on which I propose solutions to the research problems. More specifically, I have conducted research projects including:

- Viewport prediction for live 360-degree video streaming using deep video content analysis and user feedback.
- Improving the privacy and security of multimedia system following a bottomup approach, from the low-level hardware security schematic (e.g. hardware isolation) to the upper-level software algorithm (e.g. machine learning).

Besides, during my internship, I extend my research areas and focus on the problems of the next generation wireless communication (6G), using AI to solve the complicated parameters estimation of large intelligent surface. Furthermore, I am conducting research to bridge the gap between the next generation wireless communication network and the emerging multimedia system. Here is my professional summary:

- 8 peer-reviewed publications and 6 academic presentations.
- 2 undergraduate research findings.
- 2.5-year teaching experience honored with Best Teaching Assistant Award.

# PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

#### **Research Scientist**

May 2020 – August 2020

Futurewei, Wireless Communication Lab

### **Graduate Research Assistant**

September 2018 – Present

Rutgers University – New Brunswick, Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering

## **Graduate Research Assistant**

August 2016 – August 2018

University of Nebraska – Lincoln, Department of Computer Science and Engineering

#### **Graduate Research Assistant**

August 2015 - May 2016

Missouri University of Science and Technology, Department of Computer Science

#### **Graduate Research Assistant**

August 2013 - May 2015

Chinese Academy of Sciences, National Science Space Center

#### **PUBLICATIONS**

**Xianglong Feng**, Zeyang Bao, Sheng Wei, "LiveObj: Object Semantics-based Viewport Prediction for Live Mobile Virtual Reality Streaming." conditionally accepted by IEEE Conference on Virtual Reality and 3D User Interfaces (VR), March 2021.

**Xianglong Feng**, Mengmei Ye, Ke xia, Sheng Wei, "Runtime Fault Injection Detection for FPGA-based DNN Execution Using Siamese Path Verification." Design, Automation and Test in Europe (DATE), February 2021.

Sheen B, Yang J, **Xianglong Feng**, Chowdhury, M. "A Digital Twin for Reconfigurable Intelligent Surface Assisted Wireless Communication[J]". arXiv preprint arXiv:2009.00454, 2020.

Zhongze Tang, *Xianglong Feng,* Yi Xie, Huy Phan, Tian Guo, Bo Yuan, Sheng Wei, "VVSec: Securing Volumetric Video Streaming via Benign Use of Adversarial Perturbation", ACM Multimedia Conference (MM), October 2020.

**Xianglong Feng**, Yao Liu, Sheng Wei, "LiveDeep: Online Viewport Prediction for Live Virtual Reality Streaming Using Lifelong Deep Learning IEEE Conference on Virtual Reality and 3D User Interfaces (VR), March 2020

**Xianglong Feng**, Zeyang Bao, Sheng Wei, "Exploring CNN-based Viewport Prediction for Live Virtual Reality Streaming". IEEE International Conference on Artificial Intelligence and Virtual Reality (AIVR), December 2019

Mengmei Ye, *Xianglong Feng*, Sheng Wei, "Runtime Hardware Security Verification Using Approximate Computing: A Case Study on Video Motion Detection". Asian Hardware Oriented Security and Trust Symposium (AsianHOST), December 2019.

**Xianglong Feng**, Viswanathan Swaminathan, Sheng Wei, "Viewport Prediction for Live 360-Degree Mobile Video Streaming Using User-Content Hybrid Motion Tracking." Proceedings of the ACM on Interactive, Mobile, Wearable and Ubiquitous Technologies (IMWUT), 3, 2, Article 43, 22 pages, June 2019.

Mengmei Ye, *Xianglong Feng*, Sheng Wei, "HISA: Hardware Isolation-based Secure Architecture for CPU-FPGA Embedded Systems." International Conference On Computer Aided Design (ICCAD), Article No. 90, November 2018.

**Xianglong Feng**, Mengmei Ye, Viswanathan Swaminathan, Sheng Wei, "Towards the Security of Motion Detection-based Video Surveillance on IoT Devices." ACM Multimedia Conference - Thematic Workshop, October 2017.

**Xianglong Feng**, Benjie Wei, Xiujie Jiang. "Design of Video Capture and Codec based on DM368.", Electronic Design Engineering, June 2015

#### **PRESENTATIONS**

### **Oral presentation**

- "LiveDeep: Online Viewport Prediction for Live Virtual Reality Streaming Using Lifelong Deep Learning."
- "Towards the Security of Motion Detection-based Video Surveillance on IoT Devices." ACM Multimedia Conference - Thematic Workshop, October 2017.

#### **Poster Presentation**

- "Exploring CNN-based Viewport Prediction for Live Virtual Reality Streaming." IEEE AIVR 2019
- "Exploring CNN-based Viewport Prediction for Live Virtual Reality Streaming" Annual Research Day, Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering, Rutgers University, December 2019.
- "Viewport Prediction for Live 360-Degree Mobile Video Streaming Using User-Content Hybrid Motion Tracking." Annual Research Day, Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering, Rutgers University, December 2018.
- "Towards the Security of Motion Detection-based Video Surveillance on IoT Devices." ACM Multimedia Conference - Thematic Workshop, October 2017.

## **TEACHING EXPERIENCE**

## **Graduate Teaching Assistant**

Rutgers University - New Brunswick, Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering

- Digital System Design
  - o Fall 2020 (Lead TA, 123 students in lecture section, and 75 students in lab section)
  - o Fall 2019 (**Lead TA**, 145 students in lecture section, and 90 students in lab section)
  - o Fall 2018(Lead TA, 161 students in lecture section, and 102 students in lab section)
- Software Engineering
  - Spring 2019 (The only TA, 134 students)
- Computer Architecture and Assembly Code
  - Spring 2020 (42 students in the lecture and lab section)

## UNDERGRADUATE **RESEARCH GRANTS**

Large distance repeater for walkie talkie using VOIP. National University Student Innovation Program, 2010, \$1500. Role: PI

Smart sensing for modem greenhouse agriculture. College Student Innovation Program, 2009, \$300. Role: Co-Investigator

## AND AWARDS

### **ACCOMPLISHMENTS** Best Teaching Assistant

Fall 2018

ECE graduate program academic achievement award, Rutgers University.

## Academic achievement award

08/2015-12/2015

For GPA 4.0 in the first semester in Missouri University of Science and Technology.

**Qilu Software Design Contest: First Prize** 08/2010-09/2010 National Undergraduate Electronic Design Contest: Third 08/2009-09/2009

Prize

Scholarship for great academic achievement (twice) Award for GPA at top 15% (14/90), China University of Petroleum.

09/2009-09/2010

Scholarship for great innovation in science and technology 09/2009-09/2010 (twice)

Award for academic competition, China University of Petroleum.

**SERVICES** 

## **President of the Radio Association**

06/2009-06/2010